[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, are those your grandchildren?
[SPEAKER_01]: They're nice looking children.
[SPEAKER_01]: One of them, the girl graduated and is going to UC now.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then the boy's graduating from St. X High School and he'll go to St. X University.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wants to be a doctor in a way.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's taken up of all things.
[SPEAKER_02]: How many?
[SPEAKER_02]: 20.
[SPEAKER_00]: How many children did you have?
[SPEAKER_02]: Four.
[SPEAKER_00]: all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm going to keep my mouth shut.
[SPEAKER_00]: I recorded that when I said I was going to keep my mouth shut.
[SPEAKER_00]: How'd you break into baseball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, it's kind of funny.
[SPEAKER_01]: With all these bonuses and everything you got now,
[SPEAKER_01]: I got an offer to go down to Norfolk, Virginia in the Virginia League in 1916 with the promise of having my railroad fare refunded if I made good.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the bonus I got.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I think the train fare at that time amounted to about eight or ten dollars, something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that was a pretty good-sized bonus, don't you think?
[SPEAKER_01]: These guys now are getting $5,000 and $10,000 to look around.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got my train fare refunded.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who scouted you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Or who spotted you?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you, just a couple of fellas here from Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_01]: They must have heard that the Virginia League was looking for players.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that was the best offer, the only offer I ever heard or anything like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Had you played in high school or Sandlot Ball?
[SPEAKER_03]: How did they hear about you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Sandlot, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I have an idea that the way I got most of it would have been from what they call a Saturday Afternoon League.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was the best semi-pro round and it had some names.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can't, I don't think you'd remember but there was a
[SPEAKER_01]: A fellow here a few years ago, he substituted for the Reds when they ran out of ball players, and he was on that team.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can't really think what his name was.
[SPEAKER_01]: But that was about a class of the semi-pros around here.
[SPEAKER_01]: But that would be the only place.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't go to college or I didn't finish high school.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I thought that was a pretty good offer, don't you think?
[SPEAKER_02]: I get my train fare refunded.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the fellow I went with, he got released, but he got on anyway.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was that?
[SPEAKER_01]: His name was Kohlbecker, K-O-H-L-B-E-C-K-O-H-L-B-E-C-K-O-H-L-B-E-C-K-O-H-L-B-E-C-K-O-H-L-B-E-C-K-O-H-L-B-E-C-K-O-H-L-B-E-C-K-O-H-L-B-E-C-K-O-H-L-B-E-C-K-O-H-L-B-E-C-K-O-H-L-B-E-C-K-O-H-L-B-E-C-K-O-H-L-B-E-C-K-O-H-L-B-E-C
[SPEAKER_03]: He and I. Oh, could you tell us about that, how he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, we played together on a semi-pro team, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's the one that says, Ed, we got a chance to go down there and play.
[SPEAKER_01]: You want to go?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, yeah, I'd like to go.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's how we started.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then you came up with the Cubs that year.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: You played a...
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't make the Narapov team, but he went across the bay, Chesapeake Bay, and got on a
[SPEAKER_01]: what they call a Newport News team.
[SPEAKER_01]: And by the way, that name, I heard it over television the other day.
[SPEAKER_01]: They asked the question, where's Newport News?
[SPEAKER_01]: And three different states I gave.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, and the guy didn't know it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He meant Kansas, I think, or New Hampshire.
[SPEAKER_01]: And one was Virginia, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, of course, I was familiar with me and Newport News.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I guess some people never got down that way, wouldn't know it.
[SPEAKER_03]: What kind of year did you have at Norfolk that year?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you play along with them?
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's the way that happened.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you the truth, at my age I keep forgetting quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was enough that they kept me.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I played regular, but it was a real short year because it was a bad financial year.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they quit.
[SPEAKER_01]: They quit.
[SPEAKER_01]: And whoever looked halfway decent is the one that they sold if they could.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the Cubs grabbed me.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did anybody from the Cubs make any personal contact with you down there?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: You just found you were sold to the Cubs?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got a notice to report to Chicago and some kind of hotel up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I took a train.
[SPEAKER_01]: They gave me a ticket, and I went up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right in Chicago, I didn't know anybody or anything, and I went in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course,
[SPEAKER_03]: Who was the manager of the Cubs?
[SPEAKER_03]: It wasn't Fred Mitchell, was it?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, wait a minute.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tinker.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, Joe Tinker.
[SPEAKER_01]: Joe Tinker.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tinker never had a chance.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'll tell you what I'd done up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a great year up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Every time they'd have batting practice.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a short year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wasn't it 16?
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess that was the start of the war.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: Eighteen was a short year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I know that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But anyway, sixteen, well, I guess we finished out.
[SPEAKER_01]: But Heinie Zimmerman was playing third base, a fellow named Ward from Chartres, Otto Knobby, can it be?
[SPEAKER_01]: And first baseman, I can't remember.
[SPEAKER_01]: But anyway, after we'd have an infield practice, why, well, about one or two balls of Zimmerman and he had a kind
[SPEAKER_01]: tantrums or something, you know, he didn't care.
[SPEAKER_03]: Come on, kid!
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I'd have to run out there, and I'd have to finish the infield practice.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was there about three weeks or so, and the last day of the season, come to get beat nine to nothing by a fella by the name of Tyler.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was with Rudolph James and Tyler.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I think it was two out and a ninth inning, and they let me hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I hit a ground ball to the third base, and that was my big league game.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it was strictly just to give me a chance, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then during the winter, why, they sent me to Kansas City, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I took spring training in Kansas City.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now there was old, old big leaguers down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, at the time I played, there wasn't so many big league teams.
[SPEAKER_01]: There wasn't so many players.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I would say the majority of ball players were in the minor leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I played in the,
[SPEAKER_01]: American Association 12 years, and I was just right under the Bigleys.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did the Cubs own you when you went to Kansas City?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: They sold me to Kansas City.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, you were sold to Kansas City.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: How'd you do in 1917?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you see, in 1917, I took spring training with the Cubs, and they had this here Kenobi and different real big, good ball players for the Bigleys.
[SPEAKER_01]: finishing up their careers there, so I didn't have a chance.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm 18, 19 years old.
[SPEAKER_01]: So after the spring training was over, and as soon as the Texas league had started, they sold me down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I went to San Antonio, Texas.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I spent that whole year at 17 there, and then— How'd you do there, San Antonio?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I'd done this much that before the 18th season was over a month or so old, they sold me to New York Giants.
[SPEAKER_01]: The following year?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, 1918.
[SPEAKER_01]: 1917.
[SPEAKER_03]: See, I can't go ahead.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you, if I try to go back over my career, there's a few things that stand out, but to pinpoint what I'd done that year, and I don't know, I can remember this.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, I'm playing third base down in Narvauk, and all of a sudden they put me in charge
[SPEAKER_01]: So I got a good arm, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the first thing I know, I'm throwing that thing a mile over the first baseman's head.
[SPEAKER_01]: And some colored guy in his jeans said, that thing, he'll knock us right out of the stand, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I've got a great arm, and I can remember that part.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Houston was in the lake, and Waco, and teams like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it was a kind of a patched up lake, too, because Galveston was supposed to be in it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And at that time, they kind of fizzled out somewhere or another.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Dallas, Fort Worth, San Antonio, Houston.
[SPEAKER_03]: What kind of pay did you get in the Texas League?
[SPEAKER_01]: I got about a hundred and a quarter, a hundred and a half maybe at the most.
[SPEAKER_03]: A month?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I started, what did I start, seventy-five or a hundred?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't know you at that time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never got, I never, I'll tell you, that's our biggest what you call.
[SPEAKER_01]: We've been
[SPEAKER_01]: I think we've been very fortunate with our family life and everything, but we never had money.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we haven't got it now.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, we get by, we're on social security, and there's a lot of things we'd like to have.
[SPEAKER_01]: Our kids even help us out a lot.
[SPEAKER_02]: He don't want that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wants your ballplayer.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't want money, because I think with money comes some other trouble.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's my opinion.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you get expenses on the road in addition?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Those things, they took you around.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you travel?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, mostly by—well, down at Texas Lake, we traveled by train, I think, by day coach and mostly day coach.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, when you got up at Big League, it was better.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was still
[SPEAKER_01]: train, of course, you know, at that time, 1960, 18.
[SPEAKER_03]: And did you stay in pretty good hotels?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, nice hotels.
[SPEAKER_03]: Very good.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did the ballplayers suffer some kind of discrimination, you know, from the hotel people or from the public?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll be truthful with you.
[SPEAKER_01]: We generally had what they call a menu.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, we were allowed
[SPEAKER_01]: spend so much a day for our food.
[SPEAKER_01]: And of course, you'd have to look over your menu, and if you spend more than that, you'd have to pay for it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But at one time, it was about a dollar and a half a day, and you could get a breakfast for 30, 40 cents.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we didn't eat much lunch, because I was too close to the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then your supper cost a dollar, so you could get a very good supper for a dollar those days.
[SPEAKER_01]: So it was kind of adequate that way.
[SPEAKER_01]: But they would allow you so much meal money.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we could buy a real night.
[SPEAKER_01]: I liked Texas because it was warm during the day, but it was cool at night.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was real cool.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pretty hot though, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: It was warm, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But see, when you're young and run around, you don't mind that hot, especially if it's nice at night.
[SPEAKER_01]: And at night, it would be nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, of course, I was home of the Alamo and got to run out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I met some, I guess, part Mexicans or something that had a machine.
[SPEAKER_01]: They took us out there and stuff like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Texas, to me, in fact, I went in an airplane when I was there, 1970.
[SPEAKER_01]: You flew an airplane?
[SPEAKER_02]: I flew an airplane.
[SPEAKER_01]: At that time, they said that if I wanted to go in an airplane,
[SPEAKER_01]: What was the pollen years in 1918?
[SPEAKER_01]: It was spring, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you just sign your name to relieve the government of responsibility, why, they'd take you up, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: And just another guy and I go up there, and we fly all around San Antonio.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you know, 57 or 58 years ago or 55 years ago, that sounds like a long time ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was this an Army plane?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was at Camp Kelly, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kelly was quite famous at that time.
[SPEAKER_01]: And after I looked back, I said, well, I guess I didn't care about my wife.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just signed that thing and went right up there and flew around.
[SPEAKER_01]: What were the ballparks like in the Texas League?
[SPEAKER_01]: They were real nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, they were.
[SPEAKER_03]: Nice shower room facilities or locker rooms?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Most of them were like a little, you ever see the Reds at Frame House they had for their, down at Crosley Field, they had like a
[SPEAKER_01]: a little frame out there where their dressing room was and that.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was mostly on that affair.
[SPEAKER_01]: A little frame, but they had their showers.
[SPEAKER_00]: They all had showers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Would you dress in the hotel and ever dress at the ballpark?
[SPEAKER_01]: I would say like maybe a barn or something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was nothing but just a frame building and shower beds out of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, the conditions and those things were real nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: I couldn't say that I was used at all playing baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about the crowds at the Texas League games?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that's going back a little too far again.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't remember too much, but the fans weren't that big or anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had a frame that went around a little bit from first base to third base.
[SPEAKER_01]: If they had a big crowd, they'd put them on the sidelines.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you a little incident I thought was kind of cute that happened down there, and I got quite a kick out of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: After I'd been down there a while, my dad, who lived next door, you see, and I was living there, but he died in 38, you see.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was about 60-some odd years old.
[SPEAKER_01]: He decided to take a train up to Indianapolis and see me play.
[SPEAKER_01]: And of course, I was glad to see him and everything like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the way it would happen, of course, we're all introverts.
[SPEAKER_01]: We don't, you know, brag about anything or anything like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I didn't, he didn't say anybody, anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, I'll just come up and see you.
[SPEAKER_01]: But anyway, this certain day, we got a nice ballgame going.
[SPEAKER_01]: And after it's all over, then I remembered, see, it was two to two.
[SPEAKER_03]: This was when you were in Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: 2 to 2 in the ninth inning.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was right before I went up to the New York.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or no, right after, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: But anyway, 2 to 2 in the ninth inning.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's out there watching.
[SPEAKER_01]: So what do I do?
[SPEAKER_01]: It's pretty tough to get on pace and everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I did get a hit, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I stole second.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I went to third on a ground ball to the infield.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I stole home with a winning run, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: So he got a big kick out of that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought, you know, he's so proud of me.
[SPEAKER_03]: You're pretty fast, I get every, you stole a lot of bases from...
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you what kind of ball player I was, Mr. Murdock.
[SPEAKER_01]: I couldn't catch very good, not very long.
[SPEAKER_03]: Only .368 in 1928?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I got an awful lot of hits that time, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were falling over.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's just right after we got married.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a funny story.
[SPEAKER_01]: No wonder.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we got married.
[SPEAKER_01]: We were all still happy, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: You didn't win the batting title, hitting .368.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, see this Bobby Beach, he had .375, but he was only in about 110 games.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you, that's another thing I was fortunate in.
[SPEAKER_01]: I very seldom out of the game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I got you.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I was in a game, when I was out of the game, was in a fake leg, when I wanted to stay in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I put my arm up there, and I sprained my ankle up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was going real good with Philadelphia and I sprained my ankle and when I came back I couldn't, I wasn't with it.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were trying to put me in too soon or something like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I guess, have you got the averages at the association every year?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did I hit 300 every year?
[SPEAKER_03]: I have a 19, well you went down to Indianapolis in 1921.
[SPEAKER_03]: And in 285, we had a little trouble getting started there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then in 22, it was 290, 23, 290, 24, 320, 25, 316, 26, 300, 27, you went up to Pittsburgh, and then down to Indianapolis, Pittsburgh, and Louisville, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: At 303, then in 28, 368, in 29, 310, 30, 313, 31, 323.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought I was hitting 300 all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess I was in the beginning and I didn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you, baseball has changed so much.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like I say, I have no regrets.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a nice life and everything, but what do you call it?
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't have so much financially because I never made any money in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, I made more money at Indianapolis than I made in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_03]: Let me follow you through your career here now.
[SPEAKER_03]: You were sold to the Giants in 1918 and went up and played about 46 games, it says here.
[SPEAKER_03]: And who was, well, you played second base or short?
[SPEAKER_01]: I think I played third that time.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you like John McGraw?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, fine, very nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a couple of instances with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me, I'd like to hear them.
[SPEAKER_01]: You like them?
[SPEAKER_01]: Sure.
[SPEAKER_01]: in a hotel in Pittsburgh staying there when we were playing there and McGraw was walking through the lobby and this fella, he looked kind of a big, dewy sort of fella, you know, and he was popping off and finally McGraw came over to say something to me and I don't know what it was, but anyways, this fellow said to McGraw, he said,
[SPEAKER_01]: And we didn't like him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He just hauled off and let him have it and knocked him right down, right there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Right in the lobby there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, my name ain't Mugby.
[SPEAKER_01]: And gee, he was mad.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd heard that, that he didn't like that name.
[SPEAKER_01]: But McGraw was a real nice fellow, I thought.
[SPEAKER_01]: He treated me all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was one little instance, of course, that, well, it wasn't his fault either.
[SPEAKER_01]: Philadelphia needed an infielder, and they loaned me from
[SPEAKER_01]: from McGraw to Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I played a whole year with Philadelphia on a loan, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was going real good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, we heard of that arrangement.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they just loaned me over there for the year.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was going real good, and I sprained my ankle, and I lay up.
[SPEAKER_01]: And while I was going good, Philadelphia wanted to buy me.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, oh, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, that's a loan.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they got me in the office, see, and corroborate the statement.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, well,
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't really know if it was a deal or not.
[SPEAKER_01]: And McGraw, of course, says, well, I told you we were just loaning you over there, didn't I?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, what am I supposed to do?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, yeah, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: So at the end of the year, I reverted back to New York.
[SPEAKER_01]: But at the time, Philadelphia wanted to buy me.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who was their manager in Philadelphia?
[SPEAKER_01]: Philadelphia at that time was a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: I have to think of his name.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can remember certain players better, better like Lou Daris and he was the first baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Cravath still with them then?
[SPEAKER_01]: Cravath was with them, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: What kind of a guy was he?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: I would say maybe on the side of a little being a little braggadocio, I would just say that he was, I saw other fellas were nicer.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about Pat Moran?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I know who the manager was.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Moran was let go that year, I think, and went to Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, see, I was with Moran in Cincinnati when I played with Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was the average at Cincinnati?
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you have there?
[SPEAKER_03]: What's my average?
[SPEAKER_03]: 268.
[SPEAKER_03]: In 37 games.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: I thought I hit fairly good there, but... Well, tell me about your sprained ankle, was it?
[SPEAKER_03]: Or your injury at... Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_01]: Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I backed up on a fly and it was slippery and I sprained my ankle.
[SPEAKER_03]: Plane third or short?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, plane short then.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was just over 300, I thought at that time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was on, well, not just crutches, you know, but about three weeks.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they put me back in there, and my ankle wasn't right.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, I was hitting off of my front foot instead of my back foot.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, that was my ankle was on my left foot.
[SPEAKER_01]: And putting my weight on there, you got hit from your, you know, your back foot.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was hitting off of there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the first thing you know, I got off stride, and I couldn't hit nothing.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I was kind of glad the season ended, because I couldn't do nothing anymore.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you hurt your arm?
[SPEAKER_01]: In Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, that was a little later.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: OK.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Tony Bush took me up there because I played with him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I wanted to ask you about that.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was Indianapolis manager, and then he managed Pittsburgh, and you went up to Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he brought me up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I could have played there, too, if my arm didn't go bad, because I did fill in several times, and he was satisfied.
[SPEAKER_01]: But all of a sudden, a ball would come to me, and I didn't know what to do with it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I couldn't throw it.
[SPEAKER_01]: My arm was just dead.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was some kind of cord back in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had to go to, you ever hear of Bonesetter Reese?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a big shot then in the way of picking up ball players.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was from someplace in here, in Ohio, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think it's Arlington, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: But anyway, I went to him, and he said, I have a crossed cord up there or something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And while my arm never was as strong as it was before that, it didn't hurt after that anyway.
[SPEAKER_01]: They fixed it up that way.
[SPEAKER_01]: But it took me about several months before I could do any good there.
[SPEAKER_01]: So all those things were done, in my opinion, the way it was willed to be, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I wish I could have had my good arm when I went up there instead of down at Texas League and places like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can remember how good my arm was just when I was with New York.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had a field day down in Boston, and all the guys would get out in Centerfield and throw the home plates.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they finally said, Chicky, go on.
[SPEAKER_01]: Chicky, you've got good arms, you too.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I got out there with these outfielders.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was Thorpe and Burns and all of these outfielders.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they were all hitting around on their own plate, and I threw it all the way in the stand.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, I had a good arm, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: Why didn't they play in the outfield?
[SPEAKER_03]: Fast and a good arm?
[SPEAKER_03]: Maybe you should have.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wasn't a good enough hitter, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you what I was.
[SPEAKER_01]: I kind of pride myself on the fact that I thought I was a fairly smart bow player.
[SPEAKER_01]: I tried to play percentage all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Nowadays, you see guys hitting two and nothing, three and nothing, and all that stuff.
[SPEAKER_01]: That wasn't percentage for us.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, he didn't work different.
[SPEAKER_01]: If we could get that sturdy pitcher out of there,
[SPEAKER_01]: Somebody had to get in there that wasn't as good.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that was our idea.
[SPEAKER_01]: Make him work.
[SPEAKER_01]: Every time we made him throw an extra ball or so, we weakened him.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that was our strategy.
[SPEAKER_01]: And to get on base was strategy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anyway, you get on there, already advance a guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: But today, it's more individual averages, stuff like that, in my opinion.
[SPEAKER_03]: Jack Coombs.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Jack Coombs.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a real nice guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: How do you know so much about all this?
[SPEAKER_03]: I study it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you?
[SPEAKER_00]: He's a baseball nut.
[SPEAKER_00]: He must be.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what he is.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's an absolute nut.
[SPEAKER_03]: To get your averages, I went through every baseball guide for those years.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I knew you said in the associations, so I went there.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I went down the list and got your name.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I couldn't get 1917, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: That was when you were in the Texas League.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was the Texas League?
[SPEAKER_01]: San Antonio, Texas?
[SPEAKER_01]: 1916 Norfolk, then the Cubs, the 17th Texas, the quarter 17, 18, then up there.
[SPEAKER_03]: When did you go into military service?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I'll tell you what, when I was with McGraw, was that 18?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: They were going over, we were still playing, and they were going over to Boston to finish the season.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, Mac, I'm going home.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, why?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I got a notice to go in the Army.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, oh, you can make this last day.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, oh, jeez, I'm going to leave Monday or Tuesday.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that was Labor Day, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I think I went in the 4th or 5th of September.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's when he was young.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I wouldn't play.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wouldn't play that last game, because my Army career was at that time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you drafted?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, you've really played the whole season.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think the season ended, I think, back at Everett, didn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that was the end of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, he wanted me to finish out because there's only two more games, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And me, I'm thinking, oh, I'm going to the Army and they're getting shot up out of the heck with this one more game, so I come home.
[SPEAKER_03]: What about all these guys that went to the shipyards?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you remember that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I kind of remember, but not all that well.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was a form of draft evasion, almost.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I remember a few of them outstanding, but their names kind of skipped me again, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, Jackson was on, Joe Jackson was on.
[SPEAKER_01]: There were some real nice guys that had a go, I know.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, you went, I'll look at those in just a moment.
[SPEAKER_03]: I want to see those.
[SPEAKER_03]: They're very interesting.
[SPEAKER_03]: How did you happen to be traded to Cincinnati, or sold, or whatever happened?
[SPEAKER_03]: And this is 1920.
[SPEAKER_01]: Waved over.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess they were trying to wave me out of the league, and then Cincinnati claimed me.
[SPEAKER_03]: In 1920, things didn't go so well then, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: You were on loan to Philadelphia, but McGraw wanted you back.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you what really happened, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: He got a hold of Frankie Frisch.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, Frisch caused you to...
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd say I had a funny start with New York.
[SPEAKER_01]: A lot of guys, you know, you get a thrill here and there or something, but I'm in spring training with the Giants, and I'm the substitute second baseman for Larry Doyle.
[SPEAKER_01]: And a fellow by the name of Butch Baird is a substitute for Art Fletcher at Shortstop.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we're coming north, and we're playing exhibition games.
[SPEAKER_01]: We get in for a little bit, you know, and we're seeing an opening day.
[SPEAKER_01]: So the night before, Fletcher comes up with a bad sack.
[SPEAKER_01]: Baird's supposed to be the chart stop, and McGraw comes to me and says, Baird's sick.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you play short.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the next day is opening day in New York, 45,000 people at the polo grounds, and Sicking's playing short, and nobody ever heard of him.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there you go, I'm a substitute second baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm playing short in Butcher's place.
[SPEAKER_01]: But after it was all over, I didn't give it another thought.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, it ain't that you shake or anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: When you play on that, I never gave it a thought.
[SPEAKER_01]: After it was all over, I said, gee, what did I leave here?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't remember.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't do too bad.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's just like, did you ever keep that paper we had where I played with New York?
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember what I'm talking about?
[SPEAKER_03]: You don't mind if she snaps your picture, do you?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I don't mind it, but team, none of you ain't got anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yes we do.
[SPEAKER_03]: Just act natural like we were talking about.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I'll just take it when you're not even looking.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, this here particular game was put in there where New York had played Cincinnati, see, and
[SPEAKER_01]: The box score and everything was in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Larry Kopp was supposed to be playing shortstop, and I'm playing second base.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Larry called me up and said, hey, why wasn't I playing that game?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went in with Sammy Crane, was playing shortstop for the Reds.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was playing second.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, the reason I was playing was on account of Morris Rath.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was getting old, and he was getting, you know, he couldn't play regularly.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's how I happened to fill out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the next year they got Huey Critts or something like that and then I was let out again.
[SPEAKER_03]: Frisch did you out of the Giants and Critts for the Reds.
[SPEAKER_01]: If I could have hit,
[SPEAKER_01]: I could do everything else pretty good.
[SPEAKER_01]: For instance, like, I'd have one season, I'd steal 23 bases out of 26 tries.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now that's good.
[SPEAKER_01]: And a guy that would lead the league, Whit Matthews, at 50 out of 75 or something like that, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he was the leader.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I
[SPEAKER_01]: I always prided myself, Mr. Murdock, on the fact that I thought I was playing smart and doing the best I could with what I had.
[SPEAKER_03]: You're a switch hitter, right?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no, that's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: I thought you were listed in the encyclopedia as a switch hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's another thing about this.
[SPEAKER_01]: When we started out, what I thought was interesting compared to now,
[SPEAKER_01]: was that you, when you started out at that time, you had to be able to tuck a ball at your head, because everybody threw it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, if you couldn't tuck that, why, you lasted so long, and then you had to quit.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I got thrown, and I thought, well, nobody can hit me.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they'd throw, and I'd go, and I'd get up, and I was in.
[SPEAKER_01]: What impressed me more than anything else was one time, I was in the association then again, a fellow by the name of Wilkinson was a pitcher with the White Sox at one time, and he came over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: A lot of those guys came over there before or after they went to Bagley, Bill Borwell and different guys.
[SPEAKER_01]: But anyway, we're out fishing up in Minneapolis.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I come up with about a ten-pound
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was a nice looking one, we were taking a picture, and Wilkinson takes his picture and wants to send it to his daughter or something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we're having a good time, and we eight even have a little fun out there, and the next day we're playing.
[SPEAKER_01]: and comes out in about 7th or 8th inning, and it's a tie score, and I'm up there with a man on base, and Wilkinson's fishing.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you'd think that we were nice and friendly, but two or three of them right behind my ear, and I had to go.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now that's the way we played.
[SPEAKER_03]: You were fishing with him the day before?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, fishing.
[SPEAKER_01]: We took a picture and everything, just nice, good people.
[SPEAKER_01]: The pinch was the next day where he wasn't going to get beat, and I was trying to beat him, so he's going to keep me from it, and boom.
[SPEAKER_01]: Down I go, down I go.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh I got hit in the head.
[SPEAKER_01]: I threw up my arm once in a while, got hit on the shoulder and stuff like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Some graze there and there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you what they used to throw to scare you, they'd throw behind you.
[SPEAKER_01]: See?
[SPEAKER_01]: And when you stand like this, they'd throw back here.
[SPEAKER_01]: That meant the only place for you to go was down, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: You couldn't go like this and watch it go by, so you had to go down.
[SPEAKER_03]: I heard that Walter Johnson never threw at anyone because he knew he was so fast that he knew he could hurt.
[SPEAKER_03]: So he just never did it.
[SPEAKER_03]: He just...
[SPEAKER_03]: They knew this, they knew he wouldn't throw up, so they took advantage of him, they knew he was going to put it over.
[SPEAKER_01]: I like to remember the thing about him, Gordon, it was a phony, but we were playing an exhibition game against him and I got the hit against him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, did you?
[SPEAKER_01]: I got a two base hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Little things like that kind of stick in my mind.
[SPEAKER_03]: Pretty fast, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you recall that?
[SPEAKER_01]: But I, oh I, I was in the area where there was some real good play players.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, we used to, when I was in Indianapolis, Babe Ruth would come over there all the time to play exhibition games, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was a nice guy too, I thought.
[SPEAKER_03]: You got to know Babe, did you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, just a hi and that.
[SPEAKER_03]: You call your kid?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: You call your kid, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: There was a real good friend of mine pitching against him in his exhibition game, and this fella's name was Bartlett.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, I went all the way out to Iowa to go hunting with him during the off-season.
[SPEAKER_01]: His name was Bartlett, and he was pitching against Ruth his day in.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was trying that big curve, and that overhand curve, and everything like that, and he couldn't get it over.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Babes said, Bud, he said, just get it over.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't care what gets over, just get it over.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wanted to hit something, you know, but he couldn't hit the thing, because this guy was bearing down so hard.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had a lab.
[SPEAKER_01]: He turned around and he started laughing.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he hit him out of the park pretty regular, Babes said.
[SPEAKER_01]: They tell different stories about him, like up there in Indianapolis when he came here.
[SPEAKER_01]: the night before, I guess he got there the night before to play the next day, or during the day I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: But anyway he bought a, at that time, it's all, it don't sound like anything now because prices are so high now compared to then, but he bought a Victrola.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was what it was, a Victrola with I don't know how many records, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: And the head would just pass out and do that and drink, I guess, or something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when he leaves, he leaves it all lay there and just walks away.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, that was, of course, probably only cost $30, $40 then, but still that was pretty much plenty compared to what it was now.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because, you know, at that time you could buy a grocery, a bag full of groceries for $5.
[SPEAKER_03]: How did you happen to go down to Indianapolis?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did Cincy sell you there, or was there any reason why?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I got that during the winter that I was sold to Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_03]: What did you think about that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: At the time, I didn't think too much of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought maybe I'd be back again, because I thought I'd gone up there a little too soon, for one thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: But after I went down there, I liked that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, like I say, I'm an introvert.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never was that extrovert trying to get there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'll tell you what happened in Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_01]: I managed the Indianapolis team one time, only for a few weeks.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tony Bush had appendicitis operation and I was the captain.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you remember when this was, the year?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it had to be about 24, 25 in your template.
[SPEAKER_01]: You were a captain, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, oh, I was captain for quite a few years.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were you named to that?
[SPEAKER_03]: Did Bush name you captain?
[SPEAKER_03]: Or how do you, you just become a captain?
[SPEAKER_03]: I guess it's quite a tribute.
[SPEAKER_01]: The owner done it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But anyway, when it came to somebody handling the club, well, he's gone.
[SPEAKER_01]: And while I ran it, we were in third place.
[SPEAKER_01]: I ran it for almost two, three weeks.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when I get out of it, I'm in first place.
[SPEAKER_02]: But then he comes along and we wind up in second place.
[SPEAKER_01]: But now you'd think that maybe that would have urged me on to be a manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the next year, why, by gosh, I go to Louisville and they bring another manager in.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I just wasn't an extrovert enough
[SPEAKER_01]: Talk it up like DeRocher now, for instance.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played with him a half a dozen years, and I thought he was a lousy bowler.
[SPEAKER_03]: Where did you play with him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Just with St. Paul in that same league.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you have to have a gift to gab with that, and I never had that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, after I quit, I run a cafe down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I call it Sports Center, and that's all.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never did advertise that I was a ball player or anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: I bet you there's people out here
[SPEAKER_01]: Now this is a town of about 6,000 people.
[SPEAKER_01]: I would venture to say over half of them never ever heard that I was involved.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never heard of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: The real old timers, some of them still remember.
[SPEAKER_01]: But in the middle, they don't know who I am or anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because I never found out or anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like I say, I'm satisfied with my life on everything else I've had.
[SPEAKER_01]: I just can't worry about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't even know you had all of this junk yet.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now that was the first year, 1960.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now he was a real nice guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was the first baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's how I got to be confident in playing second.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd catch a ball like that and I'd say that guy over there can reach ten feet either way.
[SPEAKER_01]: All I have to do is get rid of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd get that and throw it and he'd be out there with this and that.
[SPEAKER_01]: That makes a whole lot of difference.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, did you like it in Indianapolis?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I liked it, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Very good.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you get home much there?
[SPEAKER_03]: So close?
[SPEAKER_01]: See, Mom and I weren't married then yet.
[SPEAKER_01]: We got married when I went to Louisville after that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played three years after that.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was pretty late.
[SPEAKER_02]: We got married when I was playing in this Louisville.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's Louisville.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, I was 31 years old before we got married.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was catching a ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's George Kelly there, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Eye pockets?
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me how you happened to go up then to the Pirates when Donnie Bush took you up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Or when did he go up to the Pirates?
[SPEAKER_01]: I went, how did I get up there?
[SPEAKER_01]: I must have got up there from Louisville, didn't I?
[SPEAKER_03]: What was it, 27th?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, you were both Indianapolis and Louisville.
[SPEAKER_03]: I figured you went up from Indianapolis, and then maybe you went back to Louisville.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's what happened there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bruno Betzel was with Louisville, and I was with Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they traded me for Betzel and made Betzel manager of Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_01]: Bush asked me to come up to help Pittsburgh because he had a couple of fellas, I can't think of any now, and I was doing nice up there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you get in the World Series?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were you back down?
[SPEAKER_01]: I was back already before then, yes.
[SPEAKER_03]: Why did Bush not play Kyler?
[SPEAKER_03]: Remember that business that year?
[SPEAKER_03]: Kyler was hitting .350 or something and Bush benched in the last half of the season?
[SPEAKER_03]: Remember that?
[SPEAKER_03]: Quite a scandal there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I played second with Wright, was shortstop, and Pye Traynor was third base.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was the first pitch.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that Smith, that crazy Smith was the catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oil Smith.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Kyler in the outfield was their two Wiener brothers, see?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, late in the season, he benched Wiener, put in Clyde Barnhart.
[SPEAKER_03]: Barnhart.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Barnhart was a good hitter against left-hand pitching,
[SPEAKER_01]: I just don't remember that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Apparently there was some feud between them, and then that winter he traded Cotter to the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think there was some argument there, or whatever it was.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was Pye Trainer and Wright, what were they like?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, they were real nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pye Trainer was beautiful.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was swell guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Wright, I never had any trouble.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, I didn't have any trouble with anybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never, I got along.
[SPEAKER_01]: The only guy I had trouble with was
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't have trouble with him, but I didn't like him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pat Duncan.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who was he?
[SPEAKER_03]: The Reds?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Reds.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pat Duncan.
[SPEAKER_01]: The center fielder was Eddie Roush, and Reezy Neal and Wright Beale, and Pat Duncan and Wright Beale.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when I finished up with the Reds at that time, they were splitting the World Series money.
[SPEAKER_01]: second, third, and fourth place or whatever it was, and I think we got third that year.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it was up to the players to decide what portion of that money you would get.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I think, get this now, the amount of money that they're getting now, what do we get?
[SPEAKER_01]: Third place got $400 a piece.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'm there a little over half a year.
[SPEAKER_01]: So they're deciding what part of it I should get.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was a picture of a nape here and six canes for him just in that same time I did.
[SPEAKER_01]: And anyway, they said, oh, give him a full share.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like Talbert and some of those nice guys.
[SPEAKER_01]: Another guy said, well, he's entitled to have a share.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Duncan said, give him a dime.
[SPEAKER_01]: And about three or four years after that, I run into him in a minor league.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, so you would give me a dime, would you?
[SPEAKER_01]: And he didn't say a darn word.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he could have whipped the life out of me.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a big guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were you there when he said that?
[SPEAKER_03]: Or did you hear about this?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I didn't hear.
[SPEAKER_03]: You weren't in on that?
[SPEAKER_01]: They told me.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what he said.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I had some real beautiful friends on the team, like Ivy Wingo.
[SPEAKER_01]: You ever heard of Ivy Wingo?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know much about him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know the name.
[SPEAKER_01]: But different fellows like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about Ed Roush?
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you think he'd be interviewed?
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you think he would?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he was a little upty when I knew him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did he win the batting title that year?
[SPEAKER_03]: In 1919, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: He might have.
[SPEAKER_03]: That might have been the year before.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had a little incident there that I'll show you how it works.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was playing second, he's playing center field, a little pop fly goes out there, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: We're both running after it, and bump, we hit each other, and right before we hit, the guy's hollering, Eddie, Eddie, Eddie!
[SPEAKER_03]: Which one?
[SPEAKER_03]: And we don't know which Eddie it is, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: So he said, gee, you heard him holler, Eddie, when did you get out of the road?
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, well, that's my name.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought he meant me.
[SPEAKER_01]: And, oh, you didn't know they meant me.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I go, OK, I'm not sorry anymore.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I mean, he was a little hard-headed or big-headed that way.
[SPEAKER_01]: I should have knew they meant him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't know they meant him any more than they meant me.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was poor Betty Eddie.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was dried out.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about Greasy Neal?
[SPEAKER_03]: I interviewed him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He lives over near Marietta.
[SPEAKER_03]: He did, you know, in Parkersburg.
[SPEAKER_01]: I interviewed him once.
[SPEAKER_01]: I liked him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jake Dobbin was very nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ivy Wingo was well done.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was it?
[SPEAKER_01]: McCarthy or Ketcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can't think of the English.
[SPEAKER_01]: Real nice, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Larry Kopp was good to me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I need to go.
[SPEAKER_03]: You didn't see Larry Kopp much?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't get to see him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like I say, I'm an introvert on that stuff.
[SPEAKER_01]: I should be running around and seeing all these guys.
[SPEAKER_01]: There for a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: dugout, some fella come in and run right into me and said, hey, where's Sikine at?
[SPEAKER_01]: And looking right at me, see, and Mr. Burns, no, I guess it was, yeah, I think it was Burns, said, there he is over there, see, and he pointed to some other guy over there, and this guy heard it too, see, and the guy goes over there and talks to him for five or ten minutes.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, I don't know what he said about me.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, what did you say about me?
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, oh, it's all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the guy didn't know me that well, or he wouldn't have said what he was thinking.
[SPEAKER_03]: Tell me about Joe Hauser.
[SPEAKER_03]: Joe Hauser?
[SPEAKER_01]: Wunser Joe?
[SPEAKER_03]: Wunser.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what they called him, Wunser.
[SPEAKER_01]: U-N-S-E-R, Wunser Joe.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know, not too much, outside of being a crowd head.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now that's, do you know what a crowd aide is?
[SPEAKER_03]: Not very smart.
[SPEAKER_01]: Don't you know what a crowd aide is?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's an old German.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what Frankie Fritz used to call me, Kraut.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd always call me Kraut.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think he was as Kraut as I was.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he and I played a little golf down in Florida when we were down there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who's this now?
[SPEAKER_03]: Joe?
[SPEAKER_03]: Frankie Fritz.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I didn't have too much with Hauser.
[SPEAKER_01]: He,
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a left-hand hitter, and he tried to hit as hard as he could all the time, and once in a while he'd hit one, but I don't think he was... Well, he had 69 home runs one year.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were you with him that year?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't...
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess I was, but that was an awful sharp right field.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, was that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, very sharp right field.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's a home run, the Babe Ruth of the Minor Leagues.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, and he was another fella that...
[SPEAKER_01]: I hate to say these things because it's not boosting them any.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's important that you do, though, for history's sake.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think he was overly smart.
[SPEAKER_01]: I shouldn't say stuff like that to a fella, but I mean, if he was with the power in that he had, he probably would have got further than he did, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was up with the athletics a couple years, I guess.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's pretty good years.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was he nice to associate with?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a nice fellow.
[SPEAKER_01]: Most of the players were real nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, of course, some of them were a little wild, but otherwise all players as a rule were...
[SPEAKER_01]: They got better as it went along.
[SPEAKER_01]: When I first started, you know, they had some bad reputation.
[SPEAKER_01]: I remember I'd always get a kick out of the scene
[SPEAKER_01]: And when we'd get down south in spring training, the... You better watch what you're saying.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I watched it plain.
[SPEAKER_01]: I ain't saying that bad.
[SPEAKER_01]: But these colored people down there, they'd say, you know, I'm going back 60 years or so, or no, 1916, what do you know, nearly, almost 60.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they would say,
[SPEAKER_01]: comes the ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mandy, come in here and bring that dog with you."
[SPEAKER_01]: So they didn't trust the ballplayers at all, I'll tell you the truth.
[SPEAKER_03]: But your reputation improved over the years.
[SPEAKER_01]: It improved after a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: At that time, they didn't have very much of a reputation.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I do think that they improved after that.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, right now, I think with the money they're making now, they ought to be.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you know Bunny Brief?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played against him.
[SPEAKER_01]: What's he like?
[SPEAKER_01]: It's a funny name.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's just it's easier for him to do it this way than it is to try and have them all down the stories.
[SPEAKER_01]: I haven't any impressions on him that stand out.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, nobody will ever hear that.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he always seemed like a real nice guy to me.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was quite a ball player, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought maybe it was him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played first base for Kansas City, if I remember right.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he laid the leg a few times?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was tall, right at it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I can remember that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a class in oral history.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've got to say, both of these college teams, I don't know much.
[SPEAKER_01]: A fella that used to be valuable when I played couldn't hardly get the first base now because what he's doing now isn't catching the public's eye like that home run is or anything like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Even now they're getting a little publicity on total bases, but when I played, that one that really counted was the one that was any good, otherwise it didn't mean anything.
[SPEAKER_03]: Do you remember Bevo Labarvo?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Labarvo.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is he pretty good?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, he's a nice hustler.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a guy like Pete Rose.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was hustling all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you say your husband teaches?
[SPEAKER_01]: I'll tell you one guy, trust me, he was Kinsella.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, he was with that radar.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, tell me about him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, nothing particular about him, but Dick wasn't, he didn't have too much ability, but
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd go out in the outfield, and he was a fairly good hitter, but he couldn't field at all.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he'd go out there, and somebody would hit one out there, and he'd stagger around and maybe let it fall or muffle it or something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they'd say, hey, Manoli Dick, what's the matter with you?
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd say, well, you can't see him.
[SPEAKER_01]: You can't catch him.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's just the way he felt about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He just didn't care at all if he caught it or not.
[SPEAKER_01]: His father was a scout for the New York Giants for a long time.
[SPEAKER_03]: I guess maybe that's who I was thinking of.
[SPEAKER_03]: Maybe the father.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's also a Dick?
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess he was.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I roomed with him a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a card.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who are some other players that stand out at Indianapolis New Year's there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Any particular ones?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, yeah, there was quite a few.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, Hodapp was with me over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, when he came over there and I tried to help him because I had a half a dozen years in by that time when he was just breaking in.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was playing shortstop and I was playing second base.
[SPEAKER_01]: I told him to cover one time.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't see the guy going, so at the last minute I ran over and tried to knock the ball down.
[SPEAKER_01]: I got the air for it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Stuff like that, it didn't bother me any.
[SPEAKER_01]: He, when he started, he had a hand on him twice that big, and he could run over and grab that thing like it was a meat hook, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had a lot of ability.
[SPEAKER_01]: I knew he was going some place.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because I was kind of instrumental in him signing up.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, were you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Could you tell me about that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, not particularly.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wasn't just instrumental, but they asked me if I would influence him to sign with Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: because he was holding out for a little extra money.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, at that time, if you had something to back it up, you could do it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had his business, his father's business, to back him up.
[SPEAKER_01]: I had nothing, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't even have a job.
[SPEAKER_01]: So if anybody had offered $200 for me to sign, I'd have taken it, see?
[SPEAKER_01]: And they offered him, oh, I don't know, a whole lot more, maybe $1,000 or $500, maybe $1,500, and he wanted more.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was holding out.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then the owners of Indianapolis asked me if I wouldn't talk to him and see if they wouldn't sign.
[SPEAKER_01]: And shortly after they signed, I don't know if I had any influence over him, but at least they...
[SPEAKER_03]: He was holding out with Indianapolis?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, he was holding out with Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: To go to Cleveland, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was sold to Cleveland, and he wanted a bonus of some kind, a better bonus than what they gave him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a question about him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was going to ask him, but he wouldn't let me talk to him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, he didn't say no, but he said he couldn't set a time because of his business.
[SPEAKER_03]: He didn't know when somebody was going to have a funeral, and so he couldn't set a time.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I got the idea he wasn't too eager to talk.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he had a 311 lifetime batting average in the big league, and quit baseball when he was 28 years old, or quit the Indians.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know what he did beyond that.
[SPEAKER_03]: and hit .311 his last year in the big time.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was trying to find out why he would stop playing ball at that age.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know if he went into the minor leagues after that or not, but his big league career ends in 1933.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think he just quit and went with his father's business, I'd say.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had that to fall back on all the time when you're negotiating.
[SPEAKER_01]: And these valve owners knew that.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you had something that you could negotiate with, you got a little bit more than if you were just
[SPEAKER_01]: They'd just say, well, we don't need you, so if you don't want to sign, you haven't got a job.
[SPEAKER_01]: So we'd sign with anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: I couldn't hold on at any time.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't have anything to back it up.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I'm pretty sure, I don't think there was anything wrong with him, except he did, I think, have something to do with his legs.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know if it was his knee or not.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought he had told me at one time that he went to Rome and was going up the steps or something like that and was saying a prayer on his knees or something like that for his leg.
[SPEAKER_01]: So there must have been something wrong with that.
[SPEAKER_03]: He broke his leg, Juan, in 1926.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he was out for most of the year.
[SPEAKER_03]: But then he had some good years after that.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Something with his knee or something, because he had made a promise or something that his knee would get better or his leg would get better.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he was saying certain prayers or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can kind of remember that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, you know, he is too far away from here, and I never get to see him or anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I did for a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, we used to go over the racetrack with Tony of Orange Racing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he's a good bit younger than you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was, I think he was 18 when I was about 28 or so.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was probably 10 years older than him, or close to it, maybe.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he's a busy man, that's for sure.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, and he's got a brother, Cliff.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I had a brother die here three, four years ago, George died.
[SPEAKER_01]: My brother George at HODAP had charged a funeral in, but it was Clip.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't Urban.
[SPEAKER_01]: Urban was the one that played up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Clip was the younger one.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the one up on Vine Street is the funeral establishment that handled his death.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who's that?
[SPEAKER_01]: What happened?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a good looking fellow.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever see him?
[SPEAKER_03]: I saw him play many times.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was better looking when he got older, I think, than now.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's a nice looking heir.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was one of Roger Peckinpah's pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where Gene got it.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's a copy.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the copy.
[SPEAKER_03]: From the original, you see.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's what they can do with these originals.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I was going to have him sign them.
[SPEAKER_03]: I can't see him to sign them.
[SPEAKER_03]: So, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're a little late for Heinegrohe, aren't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: I saw him over at Nurtingholm.
[SPEAKER_01]: My brother was over there at the same time he was over there, and he died over there, and my brother died over there, just about two miles away from here.
[SPEAKER_01]: My brother never married, and he was living with my married sister.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then they couldn't handle him right, and then he went over.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he play ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: But the funny part was, he was an underhanded pitcher, like Carl Mays.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was just local stuff there, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He never went out.
[SPEAKER_01]: But for the Church League or something like that, he was kind of unusual, because he'd come up like that, and go way down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: And nobody else done it around there.
[SPEAKER_03]: You were with the Reds in the season after the Black Sox World Series that year.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was there any talk of any kind of a
[SPEAKER_01]: throwing the series then?
[SPEAKER_01]: I never heard any particular because, like I say, I was there, I thought I was there a little over half a year, but I never heard anything particular.
[SPEAKER_01]: I can't say that I heard anything, any of the Reds accused them of anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Offhanded, I heard, not from them, but from around ball players and that, that they claimed some of the guys weren't trying so hard.
[SPEAKER_01]: I heard that.
[SPEAKER_03]: The White Sox?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess that was Grisberg and some of those guys that were really accused of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I didn't hear any more about that.
[SPEAKER_03]: How about Hal Chase?
[SPEAKER_03]: Were you with him at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a swell guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: What about the charges against him?
[SPEAKER_01]: That I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, we had him after that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had those at the White Sox, and he was with the Giants when I was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Real nice guy, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course I know.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought he was nice to me.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think he had any trouble with anybody.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've heard that from another old ball player, too, who was with Chase.
[SPEAKER_03]: Thought he was great and knew, couldn't say anything about these charges against him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had no knowledge of that.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wouldn't know a thing about his charges, but like I say, he got along with everybody fine.
[SPEAKER_01]: He seemed like he was a nice guy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Whatever else he'd done or anything, why, they'd have to prove it to me because he didn't appear that way to me.
[SPEAKER_01]: But, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I'm kind of glad to be talking about somebody that happened 50, 60, 70 years ago, you know, around here, where you don't get that anymore.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm fascinated by it myself.
[SPEAKER_03]: I just hear you go on and on.
[SPEAKER_01]: How old are you, Mr. Murdock?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you mind?
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll be 53 next month.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you go back that far.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I mean, I've studied.
[SPEAKER_03]: The first ballgame I saw was 1929.
[SPEAKER_03]: And HODAP was in that, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_03]: I grew up in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was out in Link Park.
[SPEAKER_03]: Saw the Yankees play Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: You told me you knew something about Crosley Field down there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I just was there once or twice.
[SPEAKER_03]: I came over here to see games.
[SPEAKER_03]: But I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was an American.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was it a big ride from Marietta down there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, about six hours.
[SPEAKER_03]: On all interstates.
[SPEAKER_03]: What are you going to do tonight?
[SPEAKER_01]: Stay at home?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, we're staying up at a motel.
[SPEAKER_03]: And we're going to see Larry Kopf in the morning and go to see Jess Haines in the afternoon.
[SPEAKER_03]: He's my first Hall of Famer.
[SPEAKER_03]: Although I'm not sure he should be in the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: Will you say hello to Larry for me?
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell him to say Ed Ziggins said one of these days he's going to come out and see you anyway.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said he tried one time and he got lost.
[SPEAKER_01]: See my daughter lives out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: In Washington.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he said, now you go down to the street here, and you go down there, and you turn, and I turn, and all of a sudden I'm out in the country someplace.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I said, I know he ain't down this far.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I come back, and I called him, and I said, I don't have time now, Larry.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, but one of these days I'm going to see you.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he talked real nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: Larry talked real nice.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd like to get the two of you together, and then I'd really have a tape.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because you can think of things I can't think of to ask, you see.
[SPEAKER_03]: You've had the experiences.
[SPEAKER_03]: heard and read about, and so I have to...
[SPEAKER_01]: The only thing I would have with Larry was, you know, a happy year playing alongside of him a little bit like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And of course, he was older than I was.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess he's 80-something now.
[SPEAKER_03]: 83, I think.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So he was older, and I guess he was married by the time I was single, and the rest of our life was apart.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, we didn't have the same impact that way.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, but Heine Groh, was he with you then?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was Heine like?
[SPEAKER_03]: With that bottled bat?
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't have any trouble with Heine.
[SPEAKER_01]: In fact, when he was sick and laying there and we talked quite a bit, he got along all right.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never had any trouble with anybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like I said, Pat Duncan, he got me bad, but he said I'd give him a dime.
[SPEAKER_03]: But all these Germans.
[SPEAKER_03]: Q.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were there a lot of Germans playing ball then for Cincinnati, or Kopf and Groh?
[SPEAKER_03]: A.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, this is a German neighborhood to start with.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cincinnati was always German, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: But, I don't know, particular.
[SPEAKER_01]: Q.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's a coincidence, probably, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: A. Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Q.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you smoke, you go ahead and smoke.
[SPEAKER_00]: Have you smoked?
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm supposed to be cutting down.
[SPEAKER_00]: My husband doesn't approve.
[SPEAKER_01]: But I will.
[SPEAKER_01]: Toughest pitcher?
[SPEAKER_01]: Toughest pitcher I think that I ever had against was Phil Douglas.
[SPEAKER_01]: Shuffling Phil.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a spitball pitcher that threw sidearm
[SPEAKER_01]: And he wasn't afraid to touch you up once in a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: So that spitter come at your head and would go over the outside corner of the plane.
[SPEAKER_01]: If it didn't break, you'd have to sit down.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I thought he was kind of tough.
[SPEAKER_03]: That the spitter went down?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, whatever way he threw it, see.
[SPEAKER_01]: If he threw it sidearm, it would go out.
[SPEAKER_01]: If he threw it overhand, it would go down.
[SPEAKER_01]: But if he threw it half sidearm and half down, he'd turn it around your head and it would go over the outside corner.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought it was very tough for me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, all of them are tough.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't hit them as good.
[SPEAKER_01]: What happened in 1928?
[SPEAKER_01]: We had that great year at Louisville.